Alexander Giannini

937 12th Street Unit 104 Santa Monica, California (310)-801-8673 alexgiannini310@gmail.com LinkedIn Profile

Objective

Seeking an opportunity where I can continue to utilize my 7 years of QA experience working with high-end clients or companies to build structured processes to strongly impact product engineering teams, while elevating my programming skills to assist with test automation coverage on multiple platforms or on any QA Engineering task at hand.

Skills

- *Tools:* Jenkins, Docker, Postman, Insomnia, ChromeDriver, TestRail API, Microsoft Teams Service, Cucumber, Azure Devops, Github, Heroku, Node.js, MongoDB, MySQL, Google Lighthouse, JMeter
- Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Gherkin, HTML, CSS, GraphQL, SQL
- Frameworks: WebdriverIO, Cypress, Selenium, React.js, Mocha, Bootstrap, Express.js
- Libraries: Chai.js, Handlebars.js

Experience

September 2021 - March 2024

Deltatre, Plava Vista - OA Engineer

- Leads QA activities on collective projects from both a manual and automation point of view
- Communicates directly with Deltatre clients to ensure high quality of products and processes
- Creates manual/automation documentation and test plans regarding QA processes, defects, release reports, tutorials, and general activities
- Gives presentations to product engineering team to provide context on updates, best QA practices, new implementations, and technological knowledge transfer
- Creates test cases on Testrails and Azure Test Plans to be conducted manually or through automation
- Conducts manual feature, UAT and regression testing for frontend/backend services for multiple projects
- Created and maintained frontend automation tests for NFL, NHL, and MLS websites using JavaScript/TypeScript, Node.js, WebdriverIO, Cypress, Mocha, and Cucumber for regression and sanity purposes, hosted on GitHub or AzureDevops
- Runs above frontend tests on remote pipelines such as Jenkins or AzureDevops designed to automatically report test results to Testrails or Azure Test Plans on a weekly/biweekly basis
- Enabled configurations within the automation test repository to run same script against numerous production and staging websites
- Produced backend automation tests for internal applications used within NFL, NHL, and IOC projects using JavaScript, Node.js, Cucumber, and an internal backend framework to provide test coverage for API endpoints
- Developed applications or hooks used before/after automated tests to ensure test data

- creation/deletion is conducted for the backend automation tests
- Designed automation tests using TypeScript and an internal framework in order to validate the SDK used within MLB's content management system built by Deltatre
- Provides code reviews to ensure programming best practices are being met
- Works with DevOps to utilize multiple continuous integration tools to execute automated tests from remote pipelines
- Performs load testing on JMeter application to ensure API endpoints or web pages used for specific projects perform at a satisfactory level
- Integrated Google Lighthouse audits within a release pipeline on Azure Devops

March 2021 - September 2021

GOAT, Culver City - QA Engineer

- Contributed to GOAT.com repository with Cypress.io unit tests
- Aligned with engineers to make sure Cypress testing coverage is up to date
- Gave code reviews to other engineers who are submitting changes to same repository
- Worked with QA to automate test cases within Testrails and Jira
- Created test plans on how to build additional coverage in meticulous manner
- Conducted manual feature testing while writing new Cypress tests in parallel with each other
- Led regression testing and creates reports of releases which include bug tickets, stories/tasks, percentage of regression passed or failed, and automated regression results run with Selenium
- Conducted production sanities and tests business critical hotfixes in minimal time
- Mentored other QA members from manual and automation point of view

October 2017 - March 2021

GOAT, Culver City - QA Analyst

- Leds team during regression testing for web and mobile platforms
- Wrote release reports which includes automated test results, manual regression results, and code changes that were included in the release
- Helped manage new feature releases on web and mobile platforms
- Worked closely with developers, product management, and design during feature testing to ensure meeting for all acceptance criterias
- Created and maintained quality of test cases
- Worked with automation team in getting tests cases to become automated
- Created bug tickets and stories which are used to elaborate on issues or improvements to a feature

Education

December 2020 - June 2021

UCLA Extension Coding Bootcamp, Los Angeles - Graduate Certificate

August 2014 - August 2017

University of the Pacific, Stockton - BA, Political Science

Awards

- UCLA Extension Full Stack Web Development Coding Boot Camp Certificate (2021)
- West Coast Conference Honorable Mention Award for singles and doubles (2017)